<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Adeep%20learning%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D5" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:deep learning&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=5</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/o6m5I8YDMO+W1ZfiBhSOoh9xyHo</id>
  <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">433865</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09997v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:58Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:58Z</published>
    <title>DGS-LRM: Real-Time Deformable 3D Gaussian Reconstruction From Monocular
  Videos</title>
    <summary>  We introduce the Deformable Gaussian Splats Large Reconstruction Model
(DGS-LRM), the first feed-forward method predicting deformable 3D Gaussian
splats from a monocular posed video of any dynamic scene. Feed-forward scene
reconstruction has gained significant attention for its ability to rapidly
create digital replicas of real-world environments. However, most existing
models are limited to static scenes and fail to reconstruct the motion of
moving objects. Developing a feed-forward model for dynamic scene
reconstruction poses significant challenges, including the scarcity of training
data and the need for appropriate 3D representations and training paradigms. To
address these challenges, we introduce several key technical contributions: an
enhanced large-scale synthetic dataset with ground-truth multi-view videos and
dense 3D scene flow supervision; a per-pixel deformable 3D Gaussian
representation that is easy to learn, supports high-quality dynamic view
synthesis, and enables long-range 3D tracking; and a large transformer network
that achieves real-time, generalizable dynamic scene reconstruction. Extensive
qualitative and quantitative experiments demonstrate that DGS-LRM achieves
dynamic scene reconstruction quality comparable to optimization-based methods,
while significantly outperforming the state-of-the-art predictive dynamic
reconstruction method on real-world examples. Its predicted physically grounded
3D deformation is accurate and can readily adapt for long-range 3D tracking
tasks, achieving performance on par with state-of-the-art monocular video 3D
tracking methods.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chieh Hubert Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhaoyang Lv</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Songyin Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhen Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thu Nguyen-Phuoc</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hung-Yu Tseng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julian Straub</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Numair Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lei Xiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming-Hsuan Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuheng Ren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Newcombe</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhao Dong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhengqin Li</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project page: https://hubert0527.github.io/dgslrm/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09997v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09997v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09998v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:58Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:58Z</published>
    <title>Flipping Against All Odds: Reducing LLM Coin Flip Bias via Verbalized
  Rejection Sampling</title>
    <summary>  Large language models (LLMs) can often accurately describe probability
distributions using natural language, yet they still struggle to generate
faithful samples from them. This mismatch limits their use in tasks requiring
reliable stochasticity, such as Monte Carlo methods, agent-based simulations,
and randomized decision-making. We investigate this gap between knowledge and
sampling in the context of Bernoulli distributions. We introduce Verbalized
Rejection Sampling (VRS), a natural-language adaptation of classical rejection
sampling that prompts the LLM to reason about and accept or reject proposed
samples. Despite relying on the same Bernoulli mechanism internally, VRS
substantially reduces sampling bias across models. We provide theoretical
analysis showing that, under mild assumptions, VRS improves over direct
sampling, with gains attributable to both the algorithm and prompt design. More
broadly, our results show how classical probabilistic tools can be verbalized
and embedded into LLM workflows to improve reliability, without requiring
access to model internals or heavy prompt engineering.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Z. Xiao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johannes Zenn</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhen Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Weiyang Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Bamler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Bernhard Schölkopf</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Technical Report v1 (21 pages, 14 figures)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09998v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09998v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09993v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:46Z</published>
    <title>Text-Aware Image Restoration with Diffusion Models</title>
    <summary>  Image restoration aims to recover degraded images. However, existing
diffusion-based restoration methods, despite great success in natural image
restoration, often struggle to faithfully reconstruct textual regions in
degraded images. Those methods frequently generate plausible but incorrect
text-like patterns, a phenomenon we refer to as text-image hallucination. In
this paper, we introduce Text-Aware Image Restoration (TAIR), a novel
restoration task that requires the simultaneous recovery of visual contents and
textual fidelity. To tackle this task, we present SA-Text, a large-scale
benchmark of 100K high-quality scene images densely annotated with diverse and
complex text instances. Furthermore, we propose a multi-task diffusion
framework, called TeReDiff, that integrates internal features from diffusion
models into a text-spotting module, enabling both components to benefit from
joint training. This allows for the extraction of rich text representations,
which are utilized as prompts in subsequent denoising steps. Extensive
experiments demonstrate that our approach consistently outperforms
state-of-the-art restoration methods, achieving significant gains in text
recognition accuracy. See our project page: https://cvlab-kaist.github.io/TAIR/
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jaewon Min</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jin Hyeon Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Hyunbin Cho</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jaeeun Lee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jihye Park</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Minkyu Park</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sangpil Kim</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hyunhee Park</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Seungryong Kim</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Project page: https://cvlab-kaist.github.io/TAIR/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09993v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09993v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09994v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:46Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:46Z</published>
    <title>eFlesh: Highly customizable Magnetic Touch Sensing using Cut-Cell
  Microstructures</title>
    <summary>  If human experience is any guide, operating effectively in unstructured
environments -- like homes and offices -- requires robots to sense the forces
during physical interaction. Yet, the lack of a versatile, accessible, and
easily customizable tactile sensor has led to fragmented, sensor-specific
solutions in robotic manipulation -- and in many cases, to force-unaware,
sensorless approaches. With eFlesh, we bridge this gap by introducing a
magnetic tactile sensor that is low-cost, easy to fabricate, and highly
customizable. Building an eFlesh sensor requires only four components: a
hobbyist 3D printer, off-the-shelf magnets (&lt;$5), a CAD model of the desired
shape, and a magnetometer circuit board. The sensor is constructed from tiled,
parameterized microstructures, which allow for tuning the sensor's geometry and
its mechanical response. We provide an open-source design tool that converts
convex OBJ/STL files into 3D-printable STLs for fabrication. This modular
design framework enables users to create application-specific sensors, and to
adjust sensitivity depending on the task. Our sensor characterization
experiments demonstrate the capabilities of eFlesh: contact localization RMSE
of 0.5 mm, and force prediction RMSE of 0.27 N for normal force and 0.12 N for
shear force. We also present a learned slip detection model that generalizes to
unseen objects with 95% accuracy, and visuotactile control policies that
improve manipulation performance by 40% over vision-only baselines -- achieving
91% average success rate for four precise tasks that require sub-mm accuracy
for successful completion. All design files, code and the CAD-to-eFlesh STL
conversion tool are open-sourced and available on https://e-flesh.com.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Venkatesh Pattabiraman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zizhou Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniele Panozzo</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Denis Zorin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Lerrel Pinto</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Raunaq Bhirangi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09994v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09994v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09991v1</id>
    <updated>2025-06-11T17:59:23Z</updated>
    <published>2025-06-11T17:59:23Z</published>
    <title>Multiverse: Your Language Models Secretly Decide How to Parallelize and
  Merge Generation</title>
    <summary>  Autoregressive Large Language Models (AR-LLMs) frequently exhibit implicit
parallelism in sequential generation. Inspired by this, we introduce
Multiverse, a new generative model that enables natively parallel generation.
Multiverse internalizes a MapReduce paradigm, generating automatically through
three stages: (i) a Map stage for adaptive task decomposition, (ii) a Process
stage for parallel subtask execution, and (iii) a Reduce stage for lossless
result synthesis. Next, we build a real-world Multiverse reasoning model with
co-design of data, algorithm, and system, enabling rapid and seamless transfer
from frontier AR-LLMs. Starting from sequential reasoning chains, we create
Multiverse 1K by converting them into structured training data using an
automated LLM-assisted pipeline, avoiding costly human annotations.
Algorithmically, we design Multiverse Attention to separate parallel reasoning
steps while keeping compatibility with causal attention for efficient training.
Systematically, we implement Multiverse Engine to enable parallel inference. It
features a dedicated scheduler that dynamically switches between sequential and
parallel generation, triggered directly by the model. After a 3-hour
fine-tuning with 1K examples, our Multiverse-32B stands as the only
open-sourced non-AR model achieving performance on par with leading AR-LLMs of
the same scale, evidenced by AIME24 &amp; 25 scores of 54% and 46%, respectively.
Moreover, our budget control experiments show that Multiverse-32B exhibits
superior scaling, outperforming AR-LLMs by 1.87% on average using the same
context length. Such scaling further leads to practical efficiency gain,
achieving up to 2x speedup across varying batch sizes. We have open-sourced the
entire Multiverse ecosystem, including data, model weights, engine, supporting
tools, as well as complete data curation prompts and detailed training and
evaluation recipes.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Xinyu Yang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuwei An</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hongyi Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tianqi Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Beidi Chen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2506.09991v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2506.09991v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
