<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Adeep%20learning%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D5" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:deep learning&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=5</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/o6m5I8YDMO+W1ZfiBhSOoh9xyHo</id>
  <updated>2025-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">413339</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15485v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-19T17:58:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-19T17:58:57Z</published>
    <title>TULIP: Towards Unified Language-Image Pretraining</title>
    <summary>  Despite the recent success of image-text contrastive models like CLIP and
SigLIP, these models often struggle with vision-centric tasks that demand
high-fidelity image understanding, such as counting, depth estimation, and
fine-grained object recognition. These models, by performing language
alignment, tend to prioritize high-level semantics over visual understanding,
weakening their image understanding. On the other hand, vision-focused models
are great at processing visual information but struggle to understand language,
limiting their flexibility for language-driven tasks. In this work, we
introduce TULIP, an open-source, drop-in replacement for existing CLIP-like
models. Our method leverages generative data augmentation, enhanced image-image
and text-text contrastive learning, and image/text reconstruction
regularization to learn fine-grained visual features while preserving global
semantic alignment. Our approach, scaling to over 1B parameters, outperforms
existing state-of-the-art (SOTA) models across multiple benchmarks,
establishing a new SOTA zero-shot performance on ImageNet-1K, delivering up to
a $2\times$ enhancement over SigLIP on RxRx1 in linear probing for few-shot
classification, and improving vision-language models, achieving over $3\times$
higher scores than SigLIP on MMVP. Our code/checkpoints are available at
https://tulip-berkeley.github.io
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zineng Tang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Long Lian</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Seun Eisape</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>XuDong Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roei Herzig</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adam Yala</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alane Suhr</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Trevor Darrell</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>David M. Chan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15485v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.15485v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15484v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-19T17:57:49Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-19T17:57:49Z</published>
    <title>Value Profiles for Encoding Human Variation</title>
    <summary>  Modelling human variation in rating tasks is crucial for enabling AI systems
for personalization, pluralistic model alignment, and computational social
science. We propose representing individuals using value profiles -- natural
language descriptions of underlying values compressed from in-context
demonstrations -- along with a steerable decoder model to estimate ratings
conditioned on a value profile or other rater information. To measure the
predictive information in rater representations, we introduce an
information-theoretic methodology. We find that demonstrations contain the most
information, followed by value profiles and then demographics. However, value
profiles offer advantages in terms of scrutability, interpretability, and
steerability due to their compressed natural language format. Value profiles
effectively compress the useful information from demonstrations (&gt;70%
information preservation). Furthermore, clustering value profiles to identify
similarly behaving individuals better explains rater variation than the most
predictive demographic groupings. Going beyond test set performance, we show
that the decoder models interpretably change ratings according to semantic
profile differences, are well-calibrated, and can help explain instance-level
disagreement by simulating an annotator population. These results demonstrate
that value profiles offer novel, predictive ways to describe individual
variation beyond demographics or group information.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Taylor Sorensen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Pushkar Mishra</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roma Patel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Henry Tessler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Michiel Bakker</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Georgina Evans</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Iason Gabriel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Noah Goodman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Verena Rieser</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15484v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.15484v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.HC" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15482v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-19T17:57:11Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-19T17:57:11Z</published>
    <title>Natural Quantization of Neural Networks</title>
    <summary>  We propose a natural quantization of a standard neural network, where the
neurons correspond to qubits and the activation functions are implemented via
quantum gates and measurements. The simplest quantized neural network
corresponds to applying single-qubit rotations, with the rotation angles being
dependent on the weights and measurement outcomes of the previous layer. This
realization has the advantage of being smoothly tunable from the purely
classical limit with no quantum uncertainty (thereby reproducing the classical
neural network exactly) to a quantum case, where superpositions introduce an
intrinsic uncertainty in the network. We benchmark this architecture on a
subset of the standard MNIST dataset and find a regime of "quantum advantage,"
where the validation error rate in the quantum realization is smaller than that
in the classical model. We also consider another approach where quantumness is
introduced via weak measurements of ancilla qubits entangled with the neuron
qubits. This quantum neural network also allows for smooth tuning of the degree
of quantumness by controlling an entanglement angle, $g$, with $g=\frac\pi 2$
replicating the classical regime. We find that validation error is also
minimized within the quantum regime in this approach. We also observe a quantum
transition, with sharp loss of the quantum network's ability to learn at a
critical point $g_c$. The proposed quantum neural networks are readily
realizable in present-day quantum computers on commercial datasets.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Barney</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Djamil Lakhdar-Hamina</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Victor Galitski</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">7 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15482v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.15482v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="quant-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.dis-nn" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15481v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-19T17:56:14Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-19T17:56:14Z</published>
    <title>Learning to Play Piano in the Real World</title>
    <summary>  Towards the grand challenge of achieving human-level manipulation in robots,
playing piano is a compelling testbed that requires strategic, precise, and
flowing movements. Over the years, several works demonstrated hand-designed
controllers on real world piano playing, while other works evaluated robot
learning approaches on simulated piano scenarios. In this paper, we develop the
first piano playing robotic system that makes use of learning approaches while
also being deployed on a real world dexterous robot. Specifically, we make use
of Sim2Real to train a policy in simulation using reinforcement learning before
deploying the learned policy on a real world dexterous robot. In our
experiments, we thoroughly evaluate the interplay between domain randomization
and the accuracy of the dynamics model used in simulation. Moreover, we
evaluate the robot's performance across multiple songs with varying complexity
to study the generalization of our learned policy. By providing a
proof-of-concept of learning to play piano in the real world, we want to
encourage the community to adopt piano playing as a compelling benchmark
towards human-level manipulation. We open-source our code and show additional
videos at https://lasr.org/research/learning-to-play-piano .
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yves-Simon Zeulner</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sandeep Selvaraj</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roberto Calandra</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15481v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.15481v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15479v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-19T17:55:40Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-19T17:55:40Z</published>
    <title>Deep Mantle-Atmosphere Coupling and Carbonaceous Bombardment: Options
  for Biomolecule Formation on an Oxidized Early Earth</title>
    <summary>  Understanding what environmental conditions prevailed on early Earth during
the Hadean eon, and how this set the stage for the origins of life, remains a
challenge. Geologic processes such as serpentinization and bombardment by
chondritic material during the late veneer might have been very active, shaping
an atmospheric composition reducing enough to allow efficient photochemical
synthesis of HCN, one of the key precursors of prebiotic molecules. HCN can
rain out and accumulate in warm little ponds (WLPs), forming prebiotic
molecules such as nucleobases and the sugar ribose. These molecules could
condense to nucleotides, the building blocks of RNA molecules, one of the
ingredients of life. Here, we perform a systematic study of potential sources
of reducing gases on Hadean Earth and calculate the concentrations of prebiotic
molecules in WLPs based on a comprehensive geophysical and atmospheric model.
We find that in a reduced H$_2$-dominated atmosphere, carbonaceous bombardment
can produce enough HCN to reach maximum WLP concentrations of $\sim
1-10\,\mathrm{mM}$ for nucleobases and, in the absence of seepage, $\sim
10-100\,\mathrm{\mu M}$ for ribose. If the Hadean atmosphere was initially
oxidized and CO$_2$-rich ($90\,\%$), we find serpentinization alone can reduce
the atmosphere, resulting in WLP concentrations of an order of magnitude lower
than the reducing carbonaceous bombardment case. In both cases, concentrations
are sufficient for nucleotide synthesis, as shown in experimental studies. RNA
could have appeared on Earth immediately after it became habitable (about
$100\,\mathrm{Myr}$ after the Moon-forming impact), or it could have
(re)appeared later at any time up to the beginning of the Archean.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Klaus Paschek</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas K. Henning</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Karan Molaverdikhani</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yoshinori Miyazaki</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ben K. D. Pearce</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ralph E. Pudritz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dmitry A. Semenov</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted for publication in The Astrophysical Journal. 44 pages, 12
  figures (all colored)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.15479v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.15479v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.ao-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
