<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Adeep%20learning%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D5" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:deep learning&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=5</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/o6m5I8YDMO+W1ZfiBhSOoh9xyHo</id>
  <updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">427948</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18152v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-23T17:59:29Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-23T17:59:29Z</published>
    <title>Fann or Flop: A Multigenre, Multiera Benchmark for Arabic Poetry
  Understanding in LLMs</title>
    <summary>  Arabic poetry stands as one of the most sophisticated and culturally embedded
forms of expression in the Arabic language, known for its layered meanings,
stylistic diversity, and deep historical continuity. Although large language
models (LLMs) have demonstrated strong performance across languages and tasks,
their ability to understand Arabic poetry remains largely unexplored. In this
work, we introduce `Fann or Flop`, the first benchmark designed to assess the
comprehension of Arabic poetry by LLMs in twelve historical eras, covering 21
core poetic genres and a variety of metrical forms, from classical structures
to contemporary free verse. The benchmark comprises a curated corpus of poems
with explanations that assess semantic understanding, metaphor interpretation,
prosodic awareness, and cultural context. We argue that poetic comprehension
offers a strong indicator for testing how good the LLM is in understanding
classical Arabic through the Arabic poetry. Unlike surface-level tasks, this
domain demands deeper interpretive reasoning and cultural sensitivity. Our
evaluation of state-of-the-art LLMs shows that most models struggle with poetic
understanding despite strong results on standard Arabic benchmarks. We release
`Fann or Flop` along with the evaluation suite as an open-source resource to
enable rigorous evaluation and advancement for Arabic language models. Code is
available at: https://github.com/mbzuai-oryx/FannOrFlop.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wafa Alghallabi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ritesh Thawkar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Ghaboura</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ketan More</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Omkar Thawakar</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hisham Cholakkal</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Salman Khan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rao Muhammad Anwer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Github:https://github.com/mbzuai-oryx/FannOrFlop,
  Dataset:https://huggingface.co/datasets/omkarthawakar/FannOrFlop</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18152v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.18152v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18150v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-23T17:58:57Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-23T17:58:57Z</published>
    <title>Generative Distribution Embeddings</title>
    <summary>  Many real-world problems require reasoning across multiple scales, demanding
models which operate not on single data points, but on entire distributions. We
introduce generative distribution embeddings (GDE), a framework that lifts
autoencoders to the space of distributions. In GDEs, an encoder acts on sets of
samples, and the decoder is replaced by a generator which aims to match the
input distribution. This framework enables learning representations of
distributions by coupling conditional generative models with encoder networks
which satisfy a criterion we call distributional invariance. We show that GDEs
learn predictive sufficient statistics embedded in the Wasserstein space, such
that latent GDE distances approximately recover the $W_2$ distance, and latent
interpolation approximately recovers optimal transport trajectories for
Gaussian and Gaussian mixture distributions. We systematically benchmark GDEs
against existing approaches on synthetic datasets, demonstrating consistently
stronger performance. We then apply GDEs to six key problems in computational
biology: learning representations of cell populations from lineage-tracing data
(150K cells), predicting perturbation effects on single-cell transcriptomes (1M
cells), predicting perturbation effects on cellular phenotypes (20M single-cell
images), modeling tissue-specific DNA methylation patterns (253M sequences),
designing synthetic yeast promoters (34M sequences), and spatiotemporal
modeling of viral protein sequences (1M sequences).
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nic Fishman</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gokul Gowri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Peng Yin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jonathan Gootenberg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Omar Abudayyeh</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18150v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.18150v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.QM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18148v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-23T17:57:42Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-23T17:57:42Z</published>
    <title>Lost in the Haystack: Smaller Needles are More Difficult for LLMs to
  Find</title>
    <summary>  Large language models (LLMs) face significant challenges with
needle-in-a-haystack tasks, where relevant information ("the needle") must be
drawn from a large pool of irrelevant context ("the haystack"). Previous
studies have highlighted positional bias and distractor quantity as critical
factors affecting model performance, yet the influence of gold context size has
received little attention. We address this gap by systematically studying how
variations in gold context length impact LLM performance on long-context
question answering tasks. Our experiments reveal that LLM performance drops
sharply when the gold context is shorter, i.e., smaller gold contexts
consistently degrade model performance and amplify positional sensitivity,
posing a major challenge for agentic systems that must integrate scattered,
fine-grained information of varying lengths. This pattern holds across three
diverse domains (general knowledge, biomedical reasoning, and mathematical
reasoning) and seven state-of-the-art LLMs of various sizes and architectures.
Our work provides clear insights to guide the design of robust, context-aware
LLM-driven systems.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Owen Bianchi</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mathew J. Koretsky</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maya Willey</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chelsea X. Alvarado</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tanay Nayak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Asija</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nicole Kuznetsov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mike A. Nalls</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Faraz Faghri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Khashabi</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Under Review</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18148v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.18148v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18147v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-23T17:57:37Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-23T17:57:37Z</published>
    <title>Nonadiabatic reactive scattering of hydrogen on different surface facets
  of copper</title>
    <summary>  Dissociative chemisorption is a key process in hydrogen-metal surface
chemistry, where nonadiabatic effects due to low-lying electron-hole-pair
excitations may affect reaction outcomes. Molecular dynamics with electronic
friction simulations can capture weak nonadiabatic effects at metal surfaces,
but require as input energy landscapes and electronic friction tensors. Here,
we present full-dimensional machine learning surrogate models of the electronic
friction tensor to study reactive hydrogen chemistry at the low-index surface
facets Cu(100), Cu(110), Cu(111), and Cu(211). We combine these surrogate
models with machine learning interatomic potentials to simulate
quantum-state-resolved H$_2$ reactive scattering on pristine copper surfaces.
The predicted sticking coefficient and survival probabilities are in excellent
agreement with experiment. Comparison between adiabatic and nonadiabatic
simulations reveals that the influence of electron-hole pair excitations on the
scattering dynamics is weak and that the probability for dissociative
adsorption is dominated by the shape of the underlying potential energy surface
and the initial vibrational quantum state. Nonadiabatic effects only lead to
subtle changes in rovibrationally inelastic state-to-state scattering
probabilities. The differences between jellium-based isotropic local density
friction and full ab-initio response-theory-based orbital-dependent friction
are even more subtle. The presented machine learning models represent the most
accurate publicly available, full-dimensional models for H$_2$ on copper to
date.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wojciech G. Stark</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Connor L. Box</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Matthias Sachs</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nils Hertl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Reinhard J. Maurer</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">16 pages, 10 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18147v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.18147v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.chem-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18145v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-23T17:55:52Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-23T17:55:52Z</published>
    <title>Stochastic agent-based Monte Carlo simulations for reaction-diffusion
  models, population dynamics, and epidemic spreading</title>
    <summary>  We provide a succinct overview of the implementation of Monte Carlo
algorithms based on Markovian stochastic dynamics to study interacting and
reacting many-particle systems away from thermal equilibrium. Such agent-based
computer simulations constitute an effective tool to introduce undergraduate
and beginning graduate students to current frontier research without requiring
much prior knowledge or experience: Starting from direct visualization of
simulation data, students may gain immediate insight into emerging macroscopic
features of a complex model system and subsequently apply more sophisticated
data analysis to quantitatively characterize its often rich dynamical
properties, both in stationary and transient regimes. We utilize numerical
investigations of paradigmatic reaction-diffusion systems, as well as
stochastic models for population dynamics and epidemic spreading, to exemplify
how interdisciplinary computational research can be effectively utilized in
bottom-up undergraduate and graduate education through learning by doing. In
addition, we give helpful hints for the practical setup of Monte Carlo
simulation algorithms, provide sample codes, explain some typical data analysis
tools, and describe various potential error sources and pitfalls, with tips for
avoiding them.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Mohamed Swailem</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ulrich Dobramysl</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ruslan Mukhamadiarov</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Uwe C. Täuber</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">66 pages, 18 figures, submitted to American Journal of Physics (2025)</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.18145v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.18145v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.stat-mech" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.PE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
