<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Adeep%20learning%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D5" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:deep learning&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=5</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/o6m5I8YDMO+W1ZfiBhSOoh9xyHo</id>
  <updated>2025-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">423872</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06228v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-09T17:59:50Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-09T17:59:50Z</published>
    <title>A Machine-Learning Compositional Study of Exoplanetary Material Accreted
  Onto Five Helium-Atmosphere White Dwarfs with $\texttt{cecilia}$</title>
    <summary>  We present the first application of the Machine Learning (ML) pipeline
$\texttt{cecilia}$ to determine the physical parameters and photospheric
composition of five metal-polluted He-atmosphere white dwarfs without
well-characterised elemental abundances. To achieve this, we perform a joint
and iterative Bayesian fit to their $\textit{SDSS}$ (R=2,000) and
$\textit{Keck/ESI}$ (R=4,500) optical spectra, covering the wavelength range
from about 3,800\r{A} to 9,000\r{A}. Our analysis measures the abundances of at
least two $-$and up to six$-$ chemical elements in their atmospheres with a
predictive accuracy similar to that of conventional WD analysis techniques
($\approx$0.20 dex). The white dwarfs with the largest number of detected heavy
elements are SDSS J0859$+$5732 and SDSS J2311$-$0041, which simultaneously
exhibit O, Mg, Si, Ca, and Fe in their $\textit{Keck/ESI}$ spectra. For all
systems, we find that the bulk composition of their pollutants is largely
consistent with those of primitive CI chondrites to within 1-2$\sigma$. We also
find evidence of statistically significant ($&gt;2\sigma$) oxygen excesses for
SDSS J0859$+$5732 and SDSS J2311$-$0041, which could point to the accretion of
oxygen-rich exoplanetary material. In the future, as wide-field astronomical
surveys deliver millions of public WD spectra to the scientific community,
$\texttt{cecilia}$ aspires to unlock population-wide studies of polluted WDs,
therefore helping to improve our statistical knowledge of extrasolar
compositions.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Mariona Badenas-Agusti</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Siyi Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Vanderburg</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kishalay De</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Patrick Dufour</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Laura K. Rogers</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Susana Hoyos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Simon Blouin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Javier Viaña</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Amy Bonsor</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ben Zuckerman</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">28 pages, 14 figures, 5 tables. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06228v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.06228v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.EP" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.IM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.SR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06227v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-09T17:59:33Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-09T17:59:33Z</published>
    <title>Anymate: A Dataset and Baselines for Learning 3D Object Rigging</title>
    <summary>  Rigging and skinning are essential steps to create realistic 3D animations,
often requiring significant expertise and manual effort. Traditional attempts
at automating these processes rely heavily on geometric heuristics and often
struggle with objects of complex geometry. Recent data-driven approaches show
potential for better generality, but are often constrained by limited training
data. We present the Anymate Dataset, a large-scale dataset of 230K 3D assets
paired with expert-crafted rigging and skinning information -- 70 times larger
than existing datasets. Using this dataset, we propose a learning-based
auto-rigging framework with three sequential modules for joint, connectivity,
and skinning weight prediction. We systematically design and experiment with
various architectures as baselines for each module and conduct comprehensive
evaluations on our dataset to compare their performance. Our models
significantly outperform existing methods, providing a foundation for comparing
future methods in automated rigging and skinning. Code and dataset can be found
at https://anymate3d.github.io/.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yufan Deng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuhao Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chen Geng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Shangzhe Wu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jiajun Wu</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">SIGGRAPH 2025. Project page: https://anymate3d.github.io/</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06227v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.06227v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06224v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-09T17:58:52Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-09T17:58:52Z</published>
    <title>Towards a Unified Representation Evaluation Framework Beyond Downstream
  Tasks</title>
    <summary>  Downstream probing has been the dominant method for evaluating model
representations, an important process given the increasing prominence of
self-supervised learning and foundation models. However, downstream probing
primarily assesses the availability of task-relevant information in the model's
latent space, overlooking attributes such as equivariance, invariance, and
disentanglement, which contribute to the interpretability, adaptability, and
utility of representations in real-world applications. While some attempts have
been made to measure these qualities in representations, no unified evaluation
framework with modular, generalizable, and interpretable metrics exists.
  In this paper, we argue for the importance of representation evaluation
beyond downstream probing. We introduce a standardized protocol to quantify
informativeness, equivariance, invariance, and disentanglement of factors of
variation in model representations. We use it to evaluate representations from
a variety of models in the image and speech domains using different
architectures and pretraining approaches on identified controllable factors of
variation. We find that representations from models with similar downstream
performance can behave substantially differently with regard to these
attributes. This hints that the respective mechanisms underlying their
downstream performance are functionally different, prompting new research
directions to understand and improve representations.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christos Plachouras</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julien Guinot</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>George Fazekas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Elio Quinton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emmanouil Benetos</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Johan Pauwels</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Accepted at IJCNN 2025</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06224v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.06224v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06223v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-09T17:57:30Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-09T17:57:30Z</published>
    <title>A Proton Treatment Planning Method for Combining FLASH and Spatially
  Fractionated Radiation Therapy to Enhance Normal Tissue Protection</title>
    <summary>  Background: FLASH radiation therapy (FLASH-RT) uses ultra-high dose rates to
induce the FLASH effect, enhancing normal tissue sparing. In proton Bragg peak
FLASH-RT, this effect is confined to high-dose regions near the target at deep
tissue levels. In contrast, Spatially Fractionated Radiation Therapy (SFRT)
creates alternating high- and low-dose regions with high peak-to-valley dose
ratios (PVDR), sparing tissues at shallow-to-intermediate depths. Purpose: This
study investigates a novel proton modality (SFRT-FLASH) that synergizes
FLASH-RT and SFRT to enhance normal tissue protection across all depths.
Methods: Two SFRT techniques are integrated with FLASH-RT: proton GRID therapy
(pGRID) with conventional beam sizes and proton minibeam radiation therapy
(pMBRT) with submillimeter beams. These are implemented as pGRID-FLASH
(SB-FLASH) and minibeam-FLASH (MB-FLASH), respectively. The pGRID technique
uses a scissor-beam (SB) method to achieve uniform target coverage. To meet
FLASH dose (5 Gy) and dose-rate (40 Gy/s) thresholds, a single-field
uniform-dose-per-fraction strategy is used. Dose and dose-rate constraints are
jointly optimized, including a CTV1cm structure (a 1 cm ring around the CTV)
for each field. Results: Across four clinical cases, MB-FLASH and SB-FLASH
plans were benchmarked against conventional (CONV), FLASH-RT (FLASH), pMBRT
(MB), and pGRID (SB) plans. SFRT-FLASH achieved high FLASH effect coverage
(~60-80% in CTV1cm) while preserving PVDR (~2.5-7) at shallow-to-intermediate
depths. Conclusions: We present a proton treatment planning approach that
combines the FLASH effect at depth with high PVDR near the surface, enhancing
normal tissue protection and advancing proton therapy.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Weijie Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Xue Hong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ya-Nan Zhu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuting Lin</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gregory Gan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ronald C Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Hao Gao</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06223v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.06223v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="physics.med-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.med-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06219v1</id>
    <updated>2025-05-09T17:54:10Z</updated>
    <published>2025-05-09T17:54:10Z</published>
    <title>VIN-NBV: A View Introspection Network for Next-Best-View Selection for
  Resource-Efficient 3D Reconstruction</title>
    <summary>  Next Best View (NBV) algorithms aim to acquire an optimal set of images using
minimal resources, time, or number of captures to enable efficient 3D
reconstruction of a scene. Existing approaches often rely on prior scene
knowledge or additional image captures and often develop policies that maximize
coverage. Yet, for many real scenes with complex geometry and self-occlusions,
coverage maximization does not lead to better reconstruction quality directly.
In this paper, we propose the View Introspection Network (VIN), which is
trained to predict the reconstruction quality improvement of views directly,
and the VIN-NBV policy. A greedy sequential sampling-based policy, where at
each acquisition step, we sample multiple query views and choose the one with
the highest VIN predicted improvement score. We design the VIN to perform
3D-aware featurization of the reconstruction built from prior acquisitions, and
for each query view create a feature that can be decoded into an improvement
score. We then train the VIN using imitation learning to predict the
reconstruction improvement score. We show that VIN-NBV improves reconstruction
quality by ~30% over a coverage maximization baseline when operating with
constraints on the number of acquisitions or the time in motion.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Noah Frahm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongxu Zhao</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Andrea Dunn Beltran</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Alterovitz</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jan-Michael Frahm</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Junier Oliva</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Roni Sengupta</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">19 pages, 11 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06219v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.06219v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="I.2.10; I.2.9" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
