<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Adeep%20learning%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D5" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:deep learning&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=5</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/o6m5I8YDMO+W1ZfiBhSOoh9xyHo</id>
  <updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">409531</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">5</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02881v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-04T18:58:21Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-04T18:58:21Z</published>
    <title>Reactive Diffusion Policy: Slow-Fast Visual-Tactile Policy Learning for
  Contact-Rich Manipulation</title>
    <summary>  Humans can accomplish complex contact-rich tasks using vision and touch, with
highly reactive capabilities such as quick adjustments to environmental changes
and adaptive control of contact forces; however, this remains challenging for
robots. Existing visual imitation learning (IL) approaches rely on action
chunking to model complex behaviors, which lacks the ability to respond
instantly to real-time tactile feedback during the chunk execution.
Furthermore, most teleoperation systems struggle to provide fine-grained
tactile / force feedback, which limits the range of tasks that can be
performed. To address these challenges, we introduce TactAR, a low-cost
teleoperation system that provides real-time tactile feedback through Augmented
Reality (AR), along with Reactive Diffusion Policy (RDP), a novel slow-fast
visual-tactile imitation learning algorithm for learning contact-rich
manipulation skills. RDP employs a two-level hierarchy: (1) a slow latent
diffusion policy for predicting high-level action chunks in latent space at low
frequency, (2) a fast asymmetric tokenizer for closed-loop tactile feedback
control at high frequency. This design enables both complex trajectory modeling
and quick reactive behavior within a unified framework. Through extensive
evaluation across three challenging contact-rich tasks, RDP significantly
improves performance compared to state-of-the-art visual IL baselines through
rapid response to tactile / force feedback. Furthermore, experiments show that
RDP is applicable across different tactile / force sensors. Code and videos are
available on https://reactive-diffusion-policy.github.io/.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Han Xue</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Jieji Ren</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Wendi Chen</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gu Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuan Fang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Guoying Gu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Huazhe Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Cewu Lu</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02881v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.02881v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02880v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-04T18:58:15Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-04T18:58:15Z</published>
    <title>A New $\sim 5σ$ Tension at Characteristic Redshift from DESI DR1
  and DES-SN5YR observations</title>
    <summary>  We perform a model-independent reconstruction of the angular diameter
distance ($D_{A}$) using the Multi-Task Gaussian Process (MTGP) framework with
DESI-DR1 BAO and DES-SN5YR datasets. We calibrate the comoving sound horizon at
the baryon drag epoch $r_d$ to the Planck best-fit value, ensuring consistency
with early-universe physics. With the reconstructed $D_A$ at two key redshifts,
$z\sim 1.63$ (where $D_{A}^{\prime} =0$) and at $z\sim 0.512$ (where
$D_{A}^{\prime} = D_{A}$), we derive the expansion rate of the Universe $H(z)$
at these redshifts. Our findings reveal that at $z\sim 1.63$, the $H(z)$ is
fully consistent with the Planck-2018 $\Lambda$CDM prediction, confirming no
new physics at that redshift. However, at $z \sim 0.512$, the derived $H(z)$
shows a more than $5\sigma$ discrepancy with the Planck-2018 $\Lambda$CDM
prediction, suggesting a possible breakdown of the $\Lambda$CDM model as
constrained by Planck-2018 at this lower redshift. This emerging $\sim 5\sigma$
tension at $z\sim 0.512$, distinct from the existing ``Hubble Tension'', may
signal the first strong evidence for new physics at low redshifts.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Purba Mukherjee</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anjan A Sen</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">4 pages, 1 table, 1 figure. Comments are welcome</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02880v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.02880v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="astro-ph.CO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="gr-qc" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="hep-th" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02879v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-04T18:58:13Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-04T18:58:13Z</published>
    <title>Wikipedia in the Era of LLMs: Evolution and Risks</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we present a thorough analysis of the impact of Large Language
Models (LLMs) on Wikipedia, examining the evolution of Wikipedia through
existing data and using simulations to explore potential risks. We begin by
analyzing page views and article content to study Wikipedia's recent changes
and assess the impact of LLMs. Subsequently, we evaluate how LLMs affect
various Natural Language Processing (NLP) tasks related to Wikipedia, including
machine translation and retrieval-augmented generation (RAG). Our findings and
simulation results reveal that Wikipedia articles have been influenced by LLMs,
with an impact of approximately 1%-2% in certain categories. If the machine
translation benchmark based on Wikipedia is influenced by LLMs, the scores of
the models may become inflated, and the comparative results among models might
shift as well. Moreover, the effectiveness of RAG might decrease if the
knowledge base becomes polluted by LLM-generated content. While LLMs have not
yet fully changed Wikipedia's language and knowledge structures, we believe
that our empirical findings signal the need for careful consideration of
potential future risks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Siming Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yuliang Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Mingmeng Geng</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yao Wan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dongping Chen</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">We release all the experimental dataset and source code at:
  https://github.com/HSM316/LLM_Wikipedia</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02879v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.02879v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CY" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02878v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-04T18:58:11Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-04T18:58:11Z</published>
    <title>Language Models can Self-Improve at State-Value Estimation for Better
  Search</title>
    <summary>  Collecting ground truth task completion rewards or human demonstrations for
multi-step reasoning tasks is often cost-prohibitive and time-consuming,
especially in interactive domains like web tasks. To address this bottleneck,
we present self-taught lookahead, a self-supervised method that leverages
state-transition dynamics to train a value model capable of effectively guiding
language model-controlled search. We find that moderately sized (8 billion
parameters) open-weight value models improved with self-taught lookahead can
match the performance of using a frontier LLM such as gpt-4o as the value
model. Furthermore, we find that self-taught lookahead improves performance by
20% while reducing costs 37x compared to previous LLM-based tree search,
without relying on ground truth rewards.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ethan Mendes</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alan Ritter</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02878v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.02878v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02877v1</id>
    <updated>2025-03-04T18:58:00Z</updated>
    <published>2025-03-04T18:58:00Z</published>
    <title>Weak-to-Strong Generalization Even in Random Feature Networks, Provably</title>
    <summary>  Weak-to-Strong Generalization (Burns et al., 2024) is the phenomenon whereby
a strong student, say GPT-4, learns a task from a weak teacher, say GPT-2, and
ends up significantly outperforming the teacher. We show that this phenomenon
does not require a strong learner like GPT-4. We consider student and teacher
that are random feature models, described by two-layer networks with a random
and fixed bottom layer and a trained top layer. A "weak" teacher, with a small
number of units (i.e. random features), is trained on the population, and a
"strong" student, with a much larger number of units (i.e. random features), is
trained only on labels generated by the weak teacher. We demonstrate, prove,
and understand how the student can outperform the teacher, even though trained
only on data labeled by the teacher. We also explain how such weak-to-strong
generalization is enabled by early stopping. Importantly, we also show the
quantitative limits of weak-to-strong generalization in this model.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Marko Medvedev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kaifeng Lyu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dingli Yu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sanjeev Arora</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhiyuan Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Nathan Srebro</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2503.02877v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2503.02877v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
